Guide to the Stanford University, Stanford Band, Records SC0334
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Stanford Band, records
1898-1988 (bulk 1963-1988)
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Marching Band
SC0334
9.5 Linear Feet
Correspondence, memos, photographs, programs, clippings, articles, handbooks, album, films from football shows, and cassette tape pertaining to performances, personnel, and history of the Stanford Band.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Transferred, 1986-2007.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memos, photographs, programs, clippings, articles, handbooks, album, films from football shows, and cassette tape pertaining to performances, personnel, and history of the Stanford Band.
Motion pictures; Band music.; Student activities.; Murray, Mike; Stanford University. Stanford Band; Stanford University. Marching Band; Stanford University. Marching Band
- Microfilm, Series 1
  - Stanford Band Musical Arrangements, 1 microfilm reel(s) (Box 1)
- Record albums, Series 2
  - Stanford Songs Medley (Burial Song; Come, Join the Band; One, Two Three, Four; Hail, Alma Mater; and Stanford Forever) [Victor 78rpm, 2 copies], circa 1926; 5; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 1)
  - Stanford Song; The Stanford Band / The Stanford Chorus [2 copies, different images on covers], circa 1950; 1; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 1)
  - The Incomparable Leland Stanford Junior University Marching Band, circa 1971; 4; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 1)
  - The Incomparable Leland Stanford Junior University Marching Band. Recorded at the Stanford Memorial Church, October 17-18, 1972; 3; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 1)
  - The Incomparable Leland Stanford Junior University Marching Band. Recorded at the Stanford Memorial Church, October 25-26, 1974; 2; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 1)
  - LSJUMB [album cover only, NO LP INSIDE], 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - The LSJUMB, 1982-1983; ARCH-2016-056; 1 audio disc(s); 1 phonograph record(s) (Box 1)
  - All Right Now (Box 1)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1986-011
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), Pre 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gavilan (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, originals (correspondence, articles, photos, and programs), 1985 fall (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1898-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - History / archives, photocopies, photographs, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Band handbook, 1964-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Band handbook, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Band handbook, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Band handbook, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Band handbook, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Oversize posters, photographs, and drawings, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1988-116
  - History / archives, photocopies, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - History / archives, photocopies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Archives, originals, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Archives, originals, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Band handbook (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters of thanks, miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Road Trip '87 [scrapbook], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rolling Stone, issue 509, "Marching Mayhem: Stanford's Band does for half time what the Marx Bros. did for opera", 1987 Sep 24 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oversize black and white stat from Rolling Stone article, 1987 Sep 24 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - LSJUMB: Contraband, 1 audio disc(s) (Box 3)
  - LSJUMB: Contraband, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Two caricatures of band members, satiric tour map, oversize black and white photograph of band members, poster for band meetign (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oversize caricature of band member (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Audiovisual materials, Accession ARCH-1989-216
  - Halftime performance--Stanford v. Arizona, 1982 Nov 6; 1.1; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 1)
  - Halftime performances (San Jose State, Duke, Washington State), 1971; 1.2-1.3; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Halftime performance--Stanford vs. Washington State, 1971; 1 audiocassette(s)
  - Stanford Band Album, 1974; 1.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Stanford Band Album, 1977, 1979; 1.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bob Butler; Frank Robertson, 1982 Aug 28-29; 1.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Robert Young, 1982 Aug 30; 1.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Don Carlson, 1.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Hal Mikkelson interview, 1.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Andy Geiger interview, 1.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2007-181
  - Harry A. Bower, ed., Imperial Method for the Drums, Timpani, Bells, Etc. (Box 1)
  - Gene Krupa, Drum Method, edited by Rollo Laylan (1938) (Box 1)
- Handbooks, 1975-1980; Accession ARCH-2015-089
  - Stanford Band Handbooks, 1975-1980 (Box 1)